Two one and we begin. Hi everyone. Hello. Welcome to intelligent disclosure. I'm Richard Dolan and my beautiful wife Tracy
Thank you. Hi everybody. Sometimes go by Tracy garbage. Sometimes Tracy garbage Dolan, whatever the mood takes you. Mm-hmm
so we're happy to be here with you again and
We're back into our group. We've been in our group for a little while since we returned from our little vacation. Yeah our trip
I just before we get into a UFOs in space again. We've got a lot of
Prepared and both of us have been sort of looking into this today. I
Just want to let people know we released a video that video an interview that I did with Frank Fasciano on
The lead-up to the Flatwoods monster case that's been it's a great interview
That is part one of a three-part interview part two
For those of you who are members of Richard
All the members and you're waiting where's the part second part of the video?
Releasing it in the morning. I've spent the day. I'm not a good video editor. You have to understand
So I dropped all the pictures in there. I wanted to make it look really right put the right maps in there
all the images takes time so
That will be available at Richard Dolan members starting tomorrow and it will be released to the public on YouTube
Next April 8th on Monday. So yes members of our site will have a little sneak
Ability to listen to that before the rest of the world, but it will be out for everyone in about a week anyway
So if you don't care and you want to wait, it'll be available and then there is a part three
That will only be for members of virtual members and we're talking
Frank and I just talked a lot about
Additional research that he did in preparation for getting all of his Flatwoods and shoot him down
Research done. I think one of the cool things about Frank's interview that you did
You know, usually you have a split-screen Skype or something like that. But this one
You it's mostly audio and the video is all of the images because Frank has kind of dedicated his life to this and
You know people have heard the Flatwoods monster case before but this
Frank has done far more research
into the
context around
Yeah, the Flatwoods monster case. So
it's really fascinating and worth a listen because
It paints a way broader picture of what was going on in the US
Yeah, you have to listen to Frank's really to appreciate him. He is the quintessential old-school
OG
Ufologist, you know, he's original gangster in my opinion. He doesn't he doesn't do Skype. He doesn't do modern technology
He's not that much older than me, but he just doesn't do it
Yeah
Well a lot of people don't but he's a heck of a researcher and so we did it on the phone
I was able to record it sounds very good and he is
So engaging he's absolutely wonderful and knows his material this case. He's devoted his whole life to it
So definitely if you haven't seen part one, it's on our channel, please take a look listen to it
It's amazing and part two again for members of ritual and members will be available tomorrow morning
And for the rest of the world in about a week, so you'll get to listen to it all
Yeah, so and you don't want to miss it. No, I mean a lot like we said a lot of people heard the story before
But this is quite different. So
Certainly worth a listen. I think a lot of us thought we knew the story until if you haven't heard it from Frank
I'm just gonna say you really don't know the story. So we'll just we could leave it at that. But yeah, that'll be available
So that's that and then for as far as Saturdays, we have a live stream on Saturdays
It's not at any particular time, but it usually ends up being sometime between 3 and 5 p.m. Eastern roughly wouldn't you say?
Yeah
If you have notifications on YouTube on the
Channel, then then you'll get notified one when it goes live
So Richard was doing the project blue book miniseries
you know where he explains the ten different cases that they did in in project loop of the series and
So, what are you thinking of doing moving forward here now that you've completed that that's all done
Well, I want to go back to you know before the blue book series
Kind of moved me in that direction. I was doing something called UFOs the big picture
I think what I want to do is just say the
Big picture and it'll sometimes be UFOs sometimes other things that are on my mind
Kind of like the way that I did the Richard Dolan show on KGRA for many years where it was just me
And a microphone doing my thing whatever was on your mind kind of thing. It's kind of what the Saturday
Broadcasts have become anyway because I don't do those with you. I just do those alone, but I I'm thinking
That's like a new new place to do
the things that are on my mind
Whether it's related to UFOs or politics false flags or whatever else I feel like talking about at that time, right?
I feel like we got a little taste of that last Saturday because a lot's on your mind
You know things are the landscape is changing as far as what we can say
On YouTube channels in different places. So I know you have a lot to say about that
Nothing I get really nervous about this and I'm being perfectly candid with you and with the listeners
I never know from week to week where YouTube's gonna be in terms of their creeping
Censorship in terms of what they allow people to say what they don't allow to say
What are they demonetized or D platform you over that the standards and rules are flexible?
They are not the same and so as a provider of content a content creator, which we are
We're in a tricky position because we deal with a subject that is has been deemed to be the fringe by YouTube
anytime we do a thing on aliens or god forbid abductions YouTube will put a
statement right below
leading you to the
Wikipedia article talking about abductions is you know, and they love to bring in words like pseudo-scientific at every possibility
They can they are so heavy-handed now with what they are
Telling us, you know what to say what not to say what's permissible. What's not permissible. I never know
So and they don't come out and say it necessarily but it comes through demonetization, which we appeal
Right. It's like if you're a author of a book, but suddenly a new laws passes says you can't make money off of your book
That's exactly what YouTube really does for creators of content these days and they just don't let you know
We haven't really had that as a problem in a major way
But it's always lurking there and they have smacked my knuckles more than once over content that I've created on this channel
And 9-11 is a big one. Yeah, they oh my god forbid they will never
That's which is too bad because that is something that continually
Needs to be explored, you know, of course
It's important and and UFOs are important. This is the thing about this subject
We know historically from the moment this became to the got to the attention of the national security elites in the 1940s
It has mattered and from that same moment
They have coordinated with what was then mainstream media to clamp down on this information?
And it's never stopped
so we've gone through kind of a revolution and communication since the 90s with internet with connectivity digital media and
for a while it was very obvious that
that hierarchy lost a little bit of control over
This narrative it couldn't control the internet right away. It was too much too wide open like the wild west
but over the last five years we have seen a
absolute
crystal clear counter-attack by them on us on our freedom to discuss things that we need to discuss
of matters that are important and what you see now is it's not like they make it illegal
they just de-rank you in search engines all right and that's very very obvious
google in particular has uh really been so so overt over the top on this you were having to
look at that today right yeah i'm going to go back more into this in the future maybe for
a saturday show we're going to be talking about space uh ufos in space but this is a real issue
and it's it bothers me more and more every week it bothers everyone yeah of course especially
knowing that you know when you're looking for something that you want that what we're probably
looking for all of us interested in these topics it's way down so it's very difficult to search
yeah you can't use google i i'm
been using duck duck go that's better that's a much better search engine it's
open source and it's not as obviously politicized as google is in the because again you have to keep
in mind whether it's google or youtube which is owned by google when you do searches there
they are absolutely uh weighted toward corporate mainstream results and it's become so much more
in the last few years than it ever was and you know really they
do this because that's the only way they can win they have to cheat otherwise no one would go to
those sites who's gonna who's gonna go to youtube and watch an nbc uh feature on ufos for god's sake
like no one would do that you go to youtube to get away from those guys and yet what google
has done through youtube is weighted uh their results toward new york times washington post
you um you know nbc abc and all of that stuff cnn um so that you
know and uh and then you know we have to figure this out because this is not going away this is
just gonna get worse and worse and my blood is starting to boil so this is why you've got to find
your your space of independence and you've got to learn how to get around this system right one
of the things that we did and i'm sure a lot of you have done things like this on your own as well
but you know we started our newsletter this was part of the reason why we did we did it for
members were requesting it we thought it would be good because we started releasing a lot of content
But also we realized, you know, we want to be able to talk to the people we want to have a way to, you know, something wherever to happen.
And that's one of the reasons why we decided to do that so that we would have that as a backup way to be able to get in touch with all of you.
It's a free newsletter. We have almost 4000 people on it now, which is really great.
So you're out there. You can get a free update on everything we're up to and you should check it out.
If you're not a subscriber to the newsletter, go to Richard Olen members or Richard Olen Press and just click. It's right there.
Yeah, that's one of the reasons we did it. And also, I just want to say to people who do get it, one thing we found, just say this really quick.
Sometimes you'll get it in your primary inbox and then all of a sudden it will be gone.
It will be they'll be going to junk or spam and it is absolutely nothing that we control.
So if you were getting it and you think you're not getting it, every single person I've looked into you are.
It's just in a different box, not where you were probably expecting it. It's moved around.
It's just something that happens to all of us. So between your browser settings and MailChimp.
And so I just want to say it's pretty stable. It will still get it to you. You just have to look for it.
So and we put it out every Sunday. We have the odd exception, but every Sunday evening, typically Eastern time.
OK, let's get into it. Shall we talk about UFOs in space? Yes, let's do it.
You've been waiting. Yes, this is what we're here for.
So this is one of the most fascinating elements of the UFO mystery, it seems to me.
I mean, we live on the ground, but we get to look up at the skies and there's there are objects that we have seen in the atmosphere.
But there are objects beyond that atmosphere. And for as long as we've had the ability to get into space,
we've had astronauts and cosmonauts who have seen things in there in space that they don't know how to explain.
I have noticed and I bet you've noticed this today that.
When you get into discussions about space based UFOs, the discussions often get nastier, even then on ground based UFOs.
You've noticed this. Yeah. Today, some things I was looking into. I definitely saw this.
Well, we're going to talk about Jeff Challenger a little later in this talk.
And I knew Jeff not well, but I knew him somewhat. Well, we like each other.
He died a little over 10 years ago. You were learning about Jeff today.
And yeah, there was a lot of nastiness against him. Yeah, but he's not alone.
Like this is and I think what it is, there's something to do with these people who want to go out and defend NASA
from some kind of accusation of conspiracy as if like you're somehow anti-American.
If you think NASA is hiding something, as Jeff always believed, as we believe, most of the people who work at NASA are great.
They're wonderful people. Brilliant, honest. There's nothing wrong with them.
But, you know, that's like people who work for a U.S. intelligence community.
They're not necessarily.
They're not necessarily bad either, but sometimes their organizations do bad things.
The fact is that there is evidence of genuine oddities in Earth orbit and beyond.
And of course, this is covered up. Like, how could it not attempted to be covered up?
And the cover up isn't perfect, but it's obviously in place, just like the remainder of the UFO phenomenon is also denied, denied, denied decade after decade.
And obviously, the same will apply for space.
But yet there seems to be a certain nastiness when you when you hear some of these debunkers and people supporting the established point of view.
It's like they maybe it's like circling the wagons because they know maybe there's something a little bit more significant up there.
I just wonder,
Mm hmm. Mm hmm.
I have something in mind, but I am not going to mention it.
But it was very distasteful.
i read today uh from a debunker it was sort of a uh character assassination on someone and it was
it was against jeff challenger and we can just we'll just say it was by james oberg who has been a
skeptic debunker and space uh matters for probably more than 40 years maybe even longer than that
and let me just say right off the bat i've read articles by him that i thought yes this is logical
and i agree with a number of his explanations i think it's important to hear what the skeptics
have to say yeah but it's also true that like every single one of his explanations all the time
is always to debunk a ufo case and it's just they're not all credible in my opinion and his
attacks on challenger were really below the belt they were just they were just really nasty um
so i want to uh can i just jump in and share a screen here please so we've got a picture of buzz
aldrin there
and everyone knows buzz aldrin second man on the moon i think buzz aldrin's
i wonder what the folks in uh nasa think of buzz is like is he becoming like the crazy old grandpa
that everyone's just afraid like what's the next thing buzz is going to say because he said
i think it's great uh i don't really know what the deal is with him i've never spoken to him
i do know his speaking engagements are expensive and
it's really hard it's a final life life thing you can live a life you shouldn't have a life
like that but even so his壦 i think his molt bones are great um he's he gets lucky um so
i like him he's really old he's still young i would think he lives in the last year or two
so when when bryce and i would did a after disclosure we couldn't afford
we wanted to get a forward by buzz aldrin i don't know if i told you no i couldn't afford it couldn't
even think about a 40 but um here's the thing about buzz so back in 2005 all right buzz aldrin
then
Like the next day. I think it was the next day or the day after that
I don't even think it was buzz. I think he had like spokespeople saying oh no
These words were taken out of context buzz Aldrin did not say such thing
and
What he actually said I just because if you do a search on buzz Aldrin UFO moon
Today, all right, you'll get like every single search result is the same the headline like Washington Post and all the others
No buzz Aldrin didn't see UFO on the way to the moon
They're all like in unison and they often use the same language, right? So they're obviously yeah, they take their marching orders
They get it from each other
But what did he actually say because what he actually said?
Was quite involved. I'm just gonna read a little bit of he just says and I should have had the
statement on
Screen here, so I apologize but he just says there's something out there that was close enough to be observed and what could it be?
Mike Mike Collins decided he thought he could see it in the telescope and he was able to do that and when it was in
One position that had a series of ellipses, but when you made it real sharp, it was sort of l-shape
That didn't tell us very much. So just consider the 2005 when he says this that's
30 what almost 40 years after the moon missions and
he
clearly is
thinking about this
to this day and then he says
Now obviously the three of us we're not going to blur it out. Hey Houston
We got something moving alongside of us and we don't know what it is, you know, can you tell us what it is?
We weren't about to do that because we knew that those transmissions would be heard by all sorts of people
Yeah, like the entire world and who knows what somebody would have demanded that we turned back because of aliens or whatever the reason is
This is all Buzz Aldrin's words
So we didn't do that, but we did decide we just cautiously asked Houston where how far away was the s4b
That's the first stage of the rocket that took the capsule out of the space a jettison that two days earlier
And we take Buzz's picture off here
They had jettisoned it a couple of days earlier
but this was something that they were pretty sure was closer than
That and they continued watching it. They fell asleep. They were still watching it. They wouldn't talk about it on the radio
I just want to point out that there's a man named. Dr. David Baker and
There was an interview that he did on the science channel. In fact, let me
Show you I think I've got his be there is so he
Had a couple of interesting things to say about this
So is one statement was NASA knew very little about the object reported by the Apollo 11 crew
It was obviously an unidentified flying object
But he says such objects were not uncommon and the history of even Earth orbit space flights going back over the previous years
Indicated that several crews saw objects. So you got to wonder like what exactly are you meaning here? Dr. Baker?
He so he goes on to say that others within NASA were also
concerned about
UFOs and this is his words. He says there were a lot of people within the program who went off later and
became convinced that UFOs existed and
That led to some concern on NASA's part where they got the agreement of the crew
Never to publicly talk about these things for fear of ridicule. So if you think about what he's saying here
first of all
Lots of people in NASA went on
So they were at NASA and they left NASA and talked about their interest in UFOs. That's absolutely true
There are quite a few of them
mention one of them in a minute marie chatelaine but baker there was really talking about what i
gathered was like a widespread culture within nasa about the reality of ufos yeah so it's just
interesting how buzz aldrin he makes these statements the media beats him up you know
with uh the structure on uh phobos the moonlit of mars that very tall tower uh which he was clearly
very he was worked up over that we should get a clip one day we're going to advance our technology
and we'll be left these nice clips yes um next step yeah but anyway so a little bit about buzz
aldrin and in fact uh before i go any further i'm just going to mention i this is almost a
cliche to mention this person here now but uh i'm talking about edgar mitchell everyone in the ufo
field knows that this man was edgar mitchell he was the first man to go to the ufos he was the
first man to go to the ufos he was the first man to go to the ufos he was the first man to go to
mitchell died a few years ago i was fortunate to know him and i had lunch and dinner with him a
few times and we talked and he was the first major public figure to endorse my work but
this is what i just want to mention this is a quote by edgar mitchell i happen to be privileged
enough to be on the to be in on the fact that we have been visited on this planet
just read that statement carefully again i happen to be privileged enough to be in
on the fact not saying i believe or i think or okay that we have been visited on this planet
and the ufo phenomenon is real yes there have been crashed craft and bodies recovered we are not alone
in the universe they've been coming here for a long time and i just want to mention i've said
this before but edgar mitchell told this to me personally uh in person back in 2004 in a very
serious one-on-one conversation
and we discussed the matter several times after that there's no question in my mind
he was absolutely telling the truth so just a little food for thought he's not talking about
ufos in space and he never did talk about that but we'll leave that for some of the
other astronauts and i do want to get into um too bad you didn't get to meet edgar mitchell by the
way that would have been nice yeah so through the 60s nasa
talked about soviet uh cosmonauts a little bit last week and if you haven't caught that i would
suggest go to our our video on soviet russian ufos and we spent like 15 minutes talking about
cosmonauts and they had some very interesting encounters but the americans did as well and
these are very argumentative among nasa people space experts on blog sites and so forth but
i i cannot i don't think it's it's fair or honest to dismiss these just because
some people say oh no we have them all explained i don't agree and one concerns um 1962 july 17th
the x-15 uh flight by major robert white now this is very early on in the u.s space program
and it was a this was a milestone event this is 58 miles up so that's that's getting into
space there's still a little bit of the atmosphere at that level but not much and uh in time magazine
he was quoted when he came back i have no idea what it could be and he's talking about something
he saw when he was up there it was grayish in color and about 30 to 40 feet away so visualize
please you're 58 miles up and something 30 or 40 feet away from you you can almost reach out and
touch that thing
i don't think that this is an accident that you're just going to see
something that just happens to be there it's obviously there for him and his statement was
there are things out there there absolutely is i would have said absolutely are but hey
that's just me there absolutely is that was his statement and i don't know how
i mean you can just say well he didn't recognize clearly what it was he saw
it too late at night there was just other people outside
so
you
know
damn
you
don't have
time
The Hawaii, and I just realized too, the, I wasn't talking about Ed White.
I was talking about, I'm screwing up here.
I'm losing my, that was Robert White and I got him mixed up with Ed White.
So forgive me.
But Ed White and James McDivitt are now in 1965.
They're in June in, over the Hawaiian islands in the Gemini spacecraft.
And they see a strange looking metallic object with long arms coming out of it.
There apparently were pictures of this that have never been released.
And all that I have heard, and that is in the public domain, is that Gordon Cooper,
another astronaut, of course, later confirmed that McDivitt did film something in space.
That's all that we really have on this.
So here's an image.
This is Ed White.
And I'm going to scroll on down here.
I'm losing all, I'm going out of order here, obviously.
So let me move on to Frank Borman and James Lovell.
So this is a situation that happened when they were in a two-week flight in space.
This is December 1965.
This is the same year as the previous one.
Borman reported that he saw an unidentified spacecraft.
Some indeterminate distance from the capsule.
So he's told to, that he was seeing the final stage of his own booster rocket, his Titan booster rocket.
And this is the interesting part.
Borman says, yes, I see the booster rocket, but I also see something completely different.
There is a radio transcript of this.
Lovell says, let me move up there.
Bogey at 10 o'clock high.
Control, this is Houston.
Say again, seven.
Said, we have a bogey at 10 o'clock high.
Gemini seven.
Is that the booster or is it an actual sighting?
We have several actual sightings.
Estimated size or distance.
And he says, we also have the booster in sight.
So take it for what it's worth.
Ken Johnson is a very interesting guy.
He's out on the lecture circuit every now and then.
If you attend conferences, you might get to meet Ken.
Tracy and I met him.
Absolute gentleman.
And he was manager of data and photo control at NASA.
He was trained as an astronaut.
There are pictures of him in his NASA spacesuits, which we have seen.
And it's very interesting that Ken is willing to go on the record to say this.
This is him being interviewed on one of the documentaries.
I assume this aired on the History Channel.
And he just talked about the Apollo 11 moon landing.
And said that, you know, we were monitored by extraterrestrials during those Apollo missions.
And he was very, very upfront about it.
He says, while Neil and Buzz were on the lunar surface,
Neil switched to the medical channel and spoke directly to the chief medical officer saying,
they're here, they're parked on the side of the crater, and they're watching us.
I'll just mention once again, I've mentioned this many times.
Timothy Good, the UK British UFO researcher,
has written about this.
He had his own totally separate source for this exact same story.
I spoke to Tim about this over a decade ago.
And his source was a woman who had been, she had died.
She overheard a conversation between Neil Armstrong and somebody else.
And they had almost the exact same conversation.
All Tim said to me was he trusted her completely.
So that's all you have to go on.
So that's, that was Ken.
And this is Donna Hare.
Donna Hare is someone that I've, I've found her testimony very compelling for many years.
And I don't ever tire of talking about what she has to say,
because I think she's really important.
She was an illustrator, a technical illustrator for Philco Ford,
that's subcontracting for NASA during the early 70s.
And she talked a number of times about when she was shown a satellite photo
of an image with a distinct UFO in it.
This is a space picture.
She was told by her colleague who showed it to her that his job was to airbrush UFOs
out of photographs before they were released to the public.
She also learned, she said that, this is over at the Johnson Space Center,
that some astronauts had seen extraterrestrial craft on the moon.
Same thing that Ken Johnson said.
Same thing that Maurice Chatelain says.
I'll get to him in a minute.
And she says, I believe that there were,
three on the moon when they landed.
The code word for UFOs was Santa Claus.
She talked also, she gave a very interesting interview in the mid 90s
for Elaine Douglas of MUFON.
Elaine has passed away, unfortunately.
And you can find this interview if you search it out.
She talked about a few other things and she had dated a man back in those days
who had been in quarantine with the astronauts when they came back from the moon.
She said she talked to him about seeing more photos of a flying saucer.
Excuse me.
She talked to him about her seeing a flying saucer in the photos and asked what he had heard about it.
And he said that every astronaut, every moon trip had been followed by craft, by saucers, she said.
This is a direct quote from her to Elaine Douglas.
They had been told to keep quiet about it.
They were threatened with jail.
And their whole retirement.
So that was the 1995 interview she did on the radio with Elaine Douglas.
And this is how a lot of these interviews go.
These people, they don't make statements for their whole life.
They make them briefly.
And in the mid 90s, she made this statement.
And and I don't know what else Donna Harris said.
This is Marie Chatelain.
And he was a manager at NASA.
He was a communications systems chief.
He has one source said he had like six patents to his name.
Another said he had 11.
I don't know how many it was.
He was clearly a man of good technical capabilities.
If you look up Marie Chatelain today, this is the wiki machine going into gear.
They don't really talk much about his technical qualifications.
They just say he's an ancient astronaut theorist.
The pseudo scientific theory of ancient astronauts.
That's how they put it.
But Chatelain was.
He was.
He was a man of definite qualifications.
And he also stated that on Apollo 11, Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin reported two UFOs on the rim of a crater.
And this is Chatelain.
He says all Apollo and Gemini flights were followed both at a distance and sometimes quite closely by space vehicles of extraterrestrial origin.
They inform Mission Control, who then said, you will not say a word about it.
Let me see if I have a quote by Chatelain in here.
Yes, he says.
The encounter of Apollo 11, he says, was common knowledge in NASA, but nobody talked about it until now.
I think that Wally Shearer, he was an astronaut aboard Mercury 8, was the first of the astronauts to use the code name Santa Claus to indicate the presence of flying saucers next to space capsules.
So, again, very interesting stuff.
This is a alleged transcript of Apollo 12.
I don't know how one could ever confirm this unless you get into classified transcripts, I suppose.
But this came through a researcher named Donald Ratsch, R-A-T-S-C-H.
And I don't know what he's up to these days, but I know that he was a very active investigator, researcher in the 80s and 90s.
And his specialty was to collect film footage from NASA space flight.
So this is kind of what Jeff Challenger did in the 90s and 2000s.
Ratsch was doing this a little earlier.
And he talked about how in 1997, a friend of his arranged for him to meet with someone who said he had worked for NASA during the Apollo space missions.
This man requested anonymity.
That's not surprising.
It's pretty typical.
But this is what he told Donald Ratsch.
During the Apollo missions, he was one of the people who sat in front of the consoles monitoring information.
And he wasn't exactly sure which mission, but he thinks it was Apollo 12, he said.
Didn't happen on Apollo 11.
And it couldn't have been Apollo 13 because they didn't make it to the moon.
Or they had problems before they even got to the moon.
But what he believes is he remembers, remembered is that one evening during one of the flights, things were slow.
There were not a lot of people around.
And so we turned into the transmissions being broadcast from the spacecraft on the, excuse me, air to ground, ground to air communication system.
They were very mundane, he said, until about 8.30 p.m. when this is what he heard.
Apollo, we have company.
Say again?
I say we have company.
A little bit of silence.
And then Houston, emphatically, you were told not to make transmissions such as that.
Put it on the flight recorder and we'll discuss it when you get back.
So that's what Ratsch was told.
Now, this is a picture of a person that I...
Received some information from about 10 years ago.
This is her in the early 80s.
This is Simone Mendez.
And she was a former Air Force telecom specialist.
She gave me her military records to review and I was able to review them.
During the early 1980s, she had top secret clearance.
This is her here while working at Nellis Air Force Base in Nevada.
She was with the 2069th Communication Squadron.
Now, what I'm saying here was...
It was mentioned in my second volume of UFOs and the National Security State.
And I do know that Simone gave a couple of interviews over the years to the Center for UFO Studies and a few other organizations.
So this has been out.
But I don't think it's very well known.
And her story is that in October 1981, a friend gave her something she was not authorized to get.
And that was the top secret message stating that NORAD had detected deep space objects entering Earth's atmosphere.
She had this in her possession for less than a day and, that's all it took.
She was apprehended, arrested I guess you could say, by Air Force police.
She went through...
And she described this very intensive, deeply unpleasant interrogation
that went on for a long time by the Air Force that really caused a lot of psychological repercussions for her.
For a long time.
After that.
this um and i just want to mention like this these are some of the documents pertaining to her case
this is absolute proof you've got her name in there and you've got the uh statement that
this was extremely sensitive material they did not say in this statement in this document what
the material was of course they're not going to but what mendez said is that these were ufos
coming in from deep space being tracked by norad so that's very very important and here's another
um document that she gave to me that i was able to review and use and again these are just
statements proving that she was who she said she was another person that i've known
for a number of years is ron reguer and ron worked he's a ufo researcher he's
was very
involved in um utah mufon utah and i don't know if he's that active in it anymore
but he's been in this field a long long time he worked in the 80s for a company
called aerojet as a defense contractor and this is his story he actually was able to get
not illegally he got this legally but it was it wasn't he wasn't supposed to get
this information it was a database from something known as the dsp that's defense
satire
program and these were a series of uh satellites or geosynchronous satellites i think there were
24 of them if i'm not mistaken and their job was to be in certain positions around the world
to monitor uh the launches of missiles so like if the russians were going to do something these
satellites were in position to detect uh the launching of those missiles and that would be
an early warning system and undoubtedly there are other uses of the dsps and in fact reguerre's
uh implementation was that they were perfect perfect us um ufo uh monitoring detectors like
right he wrote a uh a self-published book which i have a copy of how to build a 100 million dollar
ufo detector and it's all about the dsp satellites it's really good uh i have one image from that
book that i'm going to share with you guys but basically the database that he got access to it's
called the itty bitty database and it's an acronym relating to the DSP and it
had a list of all of the fast walkers that the DSP had picking up that picked
up from 1973 to 1991 18 years and it was 273 or 283 273 fast walkers about 15 a
month I think Wow so or is it 15 a year what is that 15 a month I did the math
on this a long time ago so I'm gonna figure this out to 280 say roughly
divided by 18 that's 15 a year so sorry a little more than one a month so I
don't want to make it but it's a lot and here's an image of one of them of one of
the it's not a picture this is a drawing
you
that Ron has in his book and this was one of the UFOs that was tracked on May
5th 1984 basically what happened was these things were constantly being
monitored and I'm going the wrong way here excuse me so he came into possession
of of the itty bitty stood for event target event in the vid individual
target event database
and had 283 space-based UFOs that's one more than one a month so to give you an
example every year is about 15 or more that they were tracking 1982 they tracked
15 1983 it was 17 and so forth most of one the ones that they tracked were not
deep space UFOs but some of them were and this one here from May 1984 was a deep space object a
apparently tracked by the defense satellite program and that's that's
from Ron regairs book there was a photograph that was taken and the fact
was Ron sent it to me it's not it's not the most amazing photograph I had it I've
been looking for it oh I actually you tried to get in touch time I try to get
in touch with them and like you got to get me that image again so hopefully if Ron can dig it up let me know!
get me that image again so hopefully if Ron can dig it up
I'll show it for all of you during some other so how did he get this photograph
that I think it came from the download from the download that his it came to
his company Aerojet okay and that among other things was what he was like like
oh my god look at this so yeah that would be great for us all yeah I would
like to I do remember and it's it's not a lot of detail on it so the image was
several kilometers away although in space it's not that far away like a few
kilometers truly a couple of miles and it's it was a rather indistinct image
when I looked at it I thought oh it's not really all and there's no there was
no context around it just like black and this thing however working for them he
knew what it was that it was in this sort of that category of basic class
Walker like out of context you look at it you think this is nothing at all
right it's only within context and that's one reason I wasn't all that
blown away by it
but it did come from him he's a good source and I need to get a copy of that I
may have it I just don't know where it is so anyway that's a little bit about
what's going on there that's really interesting though yeah no I want to show
all of it is but that is that is really interesting that we have this sort of
system set up and that information is sitting there and available and no one's
really reporting that to anyone what data is coming in from these
towers no exactly these are you know like the DSP for example it's all
military it's all classified like everything that comes through that is
out of our realm and there are successor satellites that are up there now that
are vastly even more sensitive I have no doubt mm-hmm it really makes you wonder
you know we're in an era now where yeah corporations Elon Musk Robert Bigelow
all these others are everyone's talking about going to space so what does that
mean
you know what does that mean does it doesn't mean that it's all gonna come
out or does it mean that they get brought into the program I don't know
you know they're talking about tourism tourism now so they do in there no well
the next few years will be really interesting in so many different ways oh
absolutely well what I think I'm gonna show some
video by the way in a minute but I guess I'll just say
I think two things are happening so one is people like Bigelow and Elon Musk
they're they're in the classified system like to the extent that they get
to be defense contractors they are bound by classified laws and regulations and
so they they can't just say oh let's tell the world about all the cool things
that we're seeing in space yeah they cannot do that however it is inevitable
that humanity is pushing more and more points more and more pressure points
going out into space pardon me and I think it's gonna be harder and harder to
contain all of that so I think there's an attempt to keep it under wraps for as
long as possible that is what's out there but I can only imagine that at
some point we're going to be looking at a necessary opening of information and
I'm starting to wonder I think that's what we're sort of seeing now with even
initiatives like TTSA
yeah otherwise that wouldn't be allowed to happen right but there is there's it's
a limited disclosure that's happening under very controlled circumstances
while at the same time most of the UFO phenomenon is being marginalized even
more by the mainstream but this little bit of UAP activity they don't even call
it UFOs is being put out there as genuine so it's a rebranding of
the
UFOs into UAP I think to make it safe for disclosure so that's what we'll have
to do if YouTube starts to get more strict we're just gonna have to create
our own language and rebrand rebrand yeah UAPs will use different words yeah
I'll just rename my books UAPs in the national security state I don't care
sounds good to me so I have a video here this is from 1984 and a number of you guys
have seen this this is the this is a very brief clip super brief clip this is
the STS 51 from May of 1954 James Oberg calls it orange juice inside the craft
in the window I'm not kidding that's what he says and he'll make fun of you
if you don't agree with him by the way so let me play this it's gonna come
through a couple of times you'll see it more than once and it's gonna come through a couple of times you'll see it more than once and
it'll be slowed down the frustrating thing about this is I have not been able
to find really good quality video decent resolution I have found better quality
resolution of this very mission this is STS 51 at least in 480p but this is I
think 360p but the 480p stuff has nothing to do with the UFO part of the
mission so go figure but let me play this does look really strange on that
frame I just have to say this is not here we go
okay there's this object it's coming in let's look at it again you're gonna see
it a few times here they slowed it down which I'm grateful for so it's obviously
a three-dimensional object it obviously has some kind of mass to it it even has
there's a shadow on the lower end of it it's spherical it could be a droplet of
some sort conceivably oh I only not showed this one yet I'm gonna show that
one later so
there we go so that was it it's just a brief little thing and I remember when I
looked at this for the first time years ago
I thought wow that's really very interesting and I didn't know too many
good photo video analysts at the time as I do now but I knew Bruce McAbee and I
asked him about it and I mean the thing about that is you can see that this
object whatever it is is definitely moving toward the camera I actually at
one point
tried my own a bit a bit to measure the size of that circle when it at the beginning and the size
of it at the end and i am certain it's a bit larger at the end so i think it's something
that's coming toward the camera if nothing else because it does seem to get a little bit larger
than um than in the beginning when i corresponded with bruce about this over a decade ago he said
uh a it's obviously it's not a hoax it is real his personal opinion was that yes nasa is probably
hiding lots of secrets on ufos in space but he wasn't sure about this particular video said i
don't really know if it shows an alien craft it could have been a reflection of something in a
window or a small nearby particle and so he he didn't know what it was and wasn't willing to
go out on a limb and i guess i'm not either but i would like to know what people think about this
i know that there are those who have opinions that it is water or orange juice inside the craft
it's hard to say i mean really it's hard to say some of these things we look at them i
mean we're not photo experts we know it looks unusual it doesn't look like some of the other
things um but it is it seems anomalous you know it seems as though it is i don't i don't think
there's there's no evidence of a reflection uh by the object in any kind of way
and i know for a fact that silence does not have to be influenced by any of the other things
that are in the window and when i just think of all the factors involved i would say it is
definitely possible that we're looking at a space anomaly you have to consider that and in my
opinion i would say that's my leading answer for it so others can disagree and be my guess but
people recording orbiting vehicles from earth that was his uh his acronym there and i uh can't
say that i was buddies with jeff challenger but i did know him we did talk uh we did correspond
a little bit we were i really admired his work and he knew that and i think he was very happy
about that uh jeff was disabled and was basically unable he was in a wheelchair uh this is his
website by the his old website he had a severe spinal injury that sort of left him housebound
pretty much yeah a long period of time and so he would he would lie on his uh stomach and recording
he had uh recordings of nasa streams going on all the time in his house and
just had a
vhs recorder and was constantly going through tapes and tapes and tapes of nasa missions and
reviewing them right i i heard he obsessively watched everything between a certain amount
of time he watched uh multiple missions but he he didn't just uh look for anomalous things
he wasn't doing it like that originally he was just doing it because he was passionate
about it and he wanted to create a documentary and after watching it for so long
and watching every second he and becoming used to what things looked like right he began to see
these anomalous things and that launched him into his research that's where he did go through second
by second all of this footage so he really did you know make an amazing contribution
i totally agree this is jeff by the way with jerry pippen uh both of them are gone now but uh jeff jeff
is very very engaged in this and just as tracy said he was uh obsessed really by this this was
the main thing and jeff he was in sacramento california he was part of a a small really
great group of sacramento ufo people i knew them all they were great people a lot of them have
moved i think they're not all there in uh in that area but he was part of it and a bunch of other
really great people so they had a nice sort of uh center of gravity there which was good anyway
a couple of videos we're going to show that jeff i think was really the first person to get into
and only only a few of these videos right now so uh the first one is called the flyby and this was
over new zealand and i just want to um be able to share the screen here properly here we go
and let me click this and hold on here
okay so this was from 1999 this is sts96 and let me just show it to you and then we'll talk about
it and there we're off to the races you'll see this is an object moving by the shuttle this is
a object that buzzed past the space shuttle complex through the lower right field of view
they were over new zealand it's very bright very close
and it's pulsing and this is in full darkness over the pacific ocean just east of new zealand
jeff had some analysis said the camera was set to infinity oh and check out the ice crystal yeah
great comparison okay and i'm just going to pause it there all right good so so he
he did a nice little analysis of it on his site he said the camera was set out to infinity obviously
uh and you see the slight difference between the sociales for the飛bal make the hitting sólido the
this object is very sharply focused. It's round. It's got a very clear outline. And in his view,
his analysis of it, and I'm not sure exactly how he comes to this, but he says, this tells us that
it was quite a bit further away than just a few feet from the camera lens. And yet its brightness
in the absence of sunlight, because it was totally dark, indicates self-illumination.
Really, I have to ask, there was no sunlight available. How is this thing reflecting or
how could it reflect so much light? That's really the question. Whereas when you see
the dust particle go by, it's very dull and it's not maneuvering in any way. It's just
straight and that's the end of it. I just want to mention as well that
the video that Richard just showed is the image enhanced. It's zoomed in, I think 200%.
Now, when Jeff presents these
typically he will show the raw footage and so you'll see uh what it actually looked like and
it was quite a bit further out and when you look at that footage that's a little uh further out
uh it is a little clearer to see that the original image is is pulsing and very bright right there's
more of a contrast between that and the ice particle you can i was just noticing in in that
zoom the ice particle actually looked a little brighter but when you see the actual footage it
is very gray very dull and it is very smooth very consistent it's completely different there's a
stark contrast between the two even more so than what you just saw in that video okay good i'm
glad you mentioned that and we should mention jeff's site project proof is to my knowledge
it's not available anywhere right now but uh he made a couple of dvds and those are available
on youtube now he used to sell them uh when he was alive and i think they they're just out on
youtube nowadays and you can probably find them that way but uh i have to say for myself
i really appreciated the way that he did it because uh he explains where the camera is
he explains uh the camera angle whether it has lights below you know what what part of
the continent it's facing in uh of north america in this case and uh or actually
sorry it wasn't north america it was over the pacific and uh when it's over water when it's
over land uh he has a lot of details that he gives and again he lets you know when it's raw footage
versus enhancements and his enhancements are excellent and in that case he had also inverted
the color yes absolutely um i'm going to show another one where he does some really excellent
enhancements and this is this has always been my personal favorite one that jeff did this is the sts
113 and uh this is from august uh 6 2005 so 21st century
uh and i'll just give a little bit of the background on this this he called this that
mission the sts-114 on his old site i'd like to find a way to make some of this more available
but he had a number of very interesting things that he recorded on that mission in 2005 but this
is uh a very interesting um and it's a very very interesting um uh little and it's one of my
favorite uh missions uh and and the main things if you've ever had a mission in light of the
atlanta mission um is a very interesting mission uh because you're in uh the northern part of
central asia and it's built in a way that everything uh you know you're in uh atlanta
yourself you have there's an island there there's a small island there at the south end of the
iowa sea and they have a more orderly life and space and that's that's what you'll see uh at the
in random motion and then among all of the things that are there you're gonna
see this one object come in that's why he calls it the wolf among the sheep so
let's play this and you can just see what we're looking at here so this is
very very smooth and this is a bit speeded up from normal I think the
actual video takes a few minutes like three minutes almost and this is a bit
speeded up and you can see it now moving back and there's other debris moving and
you can see the cloud behind it and it's moving away from that cloud and now the
camera begins to pan away and actually what ended up happening there it goes
this is a little faster watch this now here's a couple of stabilizations by
Jeff these are really interesting to see is you can actually watch the object
maneuvering
it's not simply going in a straight random pattern and that's really quite
fascinating and then he does it's almost as if it's moving it seems a left to
right or pulsing movement and he does a reverse image I think these enhancements
are very useful oh yeah absolutely and he has another one that's embossed
after this one I believe I looped them a few times just so we could see them here
we go here we go here we go here we go here we go here we go here we go here we
go I don't know how helpful the embossing one really is but again you
can see very clearly the image and it's there's a pulsing kind of movement to
this thing that is definitely interesting so there you go so so the
question is is this as ice crystals a lot of people say look it's just debris
and you know there's a there's some
something called the reaction control system these are jets on the shuttle and
they're often cited as culprits for these unusual behaviors of ice flakes
and debris and the like and that floodlights from the shuttle are
lighting up these ice particles from water the shuttles releasing this type
of thing right but the thing that really stands out in that image is of all the
debris that's that is seen in that image there's one item that does not belong
like you can see that there's a lot of debris in that image there's a lot of
debris there's a lot of debris in that image there's a lot of
debris in that image there's a lot of debris including 유면
debris under gibt
and the other one which is usually found in the geological
the audience looks
lista
a
to black so what is this thing i mean if it's some kind of dust particle it behaves i think in a very
very unusual way and um some people have argued that that thing comes to a complete stop as it
goes but his argument is that it doesn't uh that rather it it does a graceful kind of slow turn
and comes back but you'd have to you have to look at it carefully to make a decision on it
so anyway that's all the videos that we're going to show for tonight maybe we can come
back and maybe do some more of this are you going to talk about any more of jeff's or
uh i wasn't off the top of my head but if you have something you wanted to mention well yeah
if uh people want to look into it more you know you can you can find this on youtube and it is
it is an excellent little documentary that he made and he has uh what's ufo's best
best
evidence i think so ufos in space best evidence i think so um but he has several cases there and uh
they are really fascinating to watch um and he doesn't go out and say these are ufos these are
he's presenting these as anomalies for you to decide
you know do these seem anomalous to you and he does these comparisons
and he talks about what the skeptics say as well but there are examples where uh their nasa is
broadcasting and there is no sun so they just said you know the sun is about to rise and uh
they are uh the camera is just a wide uh a wide view and all of a sudden it sort of uh hones in
on something that's moving you know something that looks anomalous i mean it stands out it's moving
it's it's lit uh even though they just said there is no light source so and it's far away so it's
not like yeah it can be the same thing like we just talked about yeah it can be the same thing
the space station you know illuminating it so we have to um i'm seeing something move around in our
camera i just saw something moving around in our camera sorry um that looked really odd i'm sure
it was nothing um anyhow their camera is uh looking in it is what's the word zooming in
it's zooming in on this thing and the commentator is at a loss for words and then they cut yeah yeah
i've seen this yeah i can't remember we we should bring it back but yeah they're they're watching
this thing appear right over earth and it's pulsing it's very bright and the nasa commentator
is doing a live feed and it's a beautiful sunday morning outside chicago i think it was about one
minute from the sun coming up and he stops talking
because this thing is just right there it's pretty large but it's far away and it is
lit up completely uh flabbergasted by it yes yeah yeah i remember uh years ago i for a while i was
doing some lectures on some of these space anomalies and i remember that particular one and
i think i i played it at conferences once or twice we should find that one again but there's a number
of these embarrassingly uh funny uh moments where you could see the nasa person just doesn't know
that
what to say about it but also my point was they they're following it they were following it and
then and then they cut it right um and then there's the case in florida which i think everyone
should see where there's a big storm going on and then all of these anomalous um lights lights
pulsing lights come in at different speeds going toward the storms going towards the storm so some
of them are pulsing some of them are very slow some of them are large some of them are brighter
some of them are smaller dull and faster but they are all coming in from different angles and some
of them appear to be coming in fast and then slowing yeah so uh that's fascinating because
there are i think there are probably at least 30 of these coming in and going in towards the storm
from different angles so that's a great one for people to look at and uh you know analyze yourself
exactly keep in mind if you look at any images of earth from space there's storms
going on all the time and if you're not if you don't know what those are you'd be like
my god what's all these explosions going on in earth's atmosphere they're just normal atmospheric
storms yeah it goes on all the time yeah but but beyond that are many of these little things that
are zooming around like they are absolutely there these are not dust particles no way they've been
just too many we're gonna have to come back the way the way they're moving cannot be space debris
you know no not buying it uh so anyhow there is space debris
yes i'm i have no doubt it can oh yeah deceptive so there is you have to watch for it but these
examples do not seem like they're space space and when you have astronaut up after astronaut and
one former nasa high level insider after another after another after another saying the same thing
you really have to ask yourself okay these are not just individual people
um making yet another unrelated mistake there's obviously something going on here
there is a culture where secrecy is ordered to those people who have access to this information
and they're just not allowed to talk about it right end of story can you imagine if astronauts
could just say whatever they want well it would be out there i think it's going to happen at some
point i think that we're moving into an era where our collective species-wide push is taking more
and more of us into space it's not just america and russia's game anymore it's going to be an era
it was incredibly for more than half a century really realistically it was the americans and
the russians a couple of europeans and that was about it and now it's different so now you've got
really the entire world has got the technological capability of getting out there it's just a matter
of cost and developing an infrastructure but they all know how to do it so we're going to be
at a point where this is more widespread and that brings into question what is the nature of
global control over this subject i have argued and i'm not alone that there is global control
over this over america and its allies and i think the russians and the chinese absolutely play ball
on this and they are currently and so far willing to go along with the secrecy because it serves
their interests as well but things are in flux and you never know so i think we're moving to an era
now
where we're in a stage of a controlled form of disclosure so it's somewhat deceptive and
it's somewhat truthful you know they're giving some truth out there saying yes you know these
objects are real and then the untruth of it is we don't know what they are like they know what they
are uh but they're going through this little fiction that they don't because they have to
just like their only path forward they have to it's their only path forward
as far as they see it so they have to go through this whole thing but the danger of that is by
doing this rebranding of ufos essentially into uap um and sort of sanitizing the rest of the field
like they are really working hard to sanitize the ufo subject so that it's only these unknown uap
so sanitizing crash retrievals out sanitizing genuine space-based ufos out
sanitizing uh reverse engineering of alien tech out and alien biology all of that gets out
and only this unknown uap is likely to be acknowledged in the future and you can see
how heavy-handed the uh the corporate mainstream establishment system is now in controlling this
discussion they're making it more and more difficult for alternative viewpoints like
the whole rest of the world to express what is what is true and what is
worthy of scientific discussion and they're just pushing it out it's not not to be discussed so
that's my my biggest fear is that they're they're going to be able to do a disclosure
and i would never have thought 10 years ago that they'd be able to get away with it on their terms
right like i didn't think that that would be possible right i thought you can't be half
pregnant you can't have disclose
but i think honestly that those people who are running this believe they can have disclose
and the truth is they might be able to right if we kind of look that way if we let them get away
with it so it's up it's up to all of us who care about this to uh continue to push on this matter
and it's a good thing that there's a measure of disclosure happening but we cannot allow
the spin on that uh that's coming down to us just to be unchallenged like we've got to challenge
that spin and that's what we're doing with this program now like there's we've just given a sliver
of what's going on in space there's a tremendous amount of activity there
tremendous is there anything else you you did a lot of uh diving in well i i was really into
jeff's stuff today and uh like i said before i really encourage people to go and check it out for
yourselves um
he brings up methods that you know from watching so much footage that he thinks
NASA is obscuring the picture on purpose so that they can kind of manage what's
what people are seeing oh right the creation of non-legitimate snow on the
pictures right and the reason I mean you could just say that and I'm sure they
would have something to say against that but what he does show you is there are
images where they'll switch to a camera and it's clear and then all of a sudden
it's like someone flicks a switch and then it's snow it's like it's not
completely unwatchable but it's much less watchable and the snow does seem to
go over the NASA logo so it seems like it's superimposed over yeah so he makes
a good case that they are really managing this situation of all of these
anomalous objects that well yeah and then there's the whole delay
20-second delay right so they've got it at least a 20-second delay and and this
was confirmed actually by Russians during one of the joint missions on the
International Space Station the Russians were relying on a US feed and the
Russian cosmonaut said a little bit of an issue where your NASA feeds are 20
minutes late it's okay we can deal with it and he provided this footage because
again he was watching and recording everything so he caught this himself so
it's a documentary that is on YouTube right but he showed there were other
ways as well that he felt they were obscuring the picture to manage this so
that was just something but there are he has a few different cases that are worth
looking at yeah I would absolutely agree so yeah I was kind of focused on him
today that was my one odd thing about Jeff he died in 2007 oh yes October of
07 I happened to be in France at that time I was there for about a week and
for whatever reason in the week leading up to his death yeah right Jeff
Challenger Challenger was really on my mind I was talking about his work to
everyone who would listen and I just saw I said no he is very very important and
he needs to be more recognized for what he's doing and then he died just as I was
going through his website I thought you know in case something happens right
I want to rip this man's website I don't know how how good that is or not
but I did it and I'm very glad I did because then he he wanted a backup is
what that's exactly what it was because I didn't know how secure his site would
be it was just this uh weird intuition maybe I had I don't know but anyway and
then he died like right then and yeah he had a massive heart attack yeah very in
weight died way too young but um you know we're we're lucky that we had him
and I'm glad his
these are out on YouTube so you can go check those out um and then of course
with space I mean we have you know the whole Gary McKinnon story well we talked
to Gary not long ago and that's a great interview and in fact it was his first
major interview in forever for ages and ages so please do go check it out one
other interesting story that I'll share I wrote about this but I I don't know if
I've ever talked about it so when I was 21 years old
I was
it was two days after I turned 21 it was July 3rd 1983 right my birthday's July 1st and so I was I
just turned 21 and I was in the Newark airport Newark New Jersey about to fly to the UK uh I
was about to leave the country for the first time and so I was alone in this airport causing any
trouble then now I was too scared I didn't I was just trying to get my way through the airport you
know so I remembered waiting
and um they had TVs on the wall back then just as they do now and I remember just sort of
aimlessly watching the TV news because there's nothing else to do at that moment and it was a
news story on the strategic defense initiative SDI known as Star Wars
President Ronald Reagan had announced the Star Wars Star Wars program SDI back in March of 83
so in July of 83.
Star Wars was very much in the news people were talking about it so I didn't
really wasn't following it at all or anything beyond just casual you know
casual news reading and the while I was watching it this man and maybe in his
40s very well-dressed gray suit walks up and he's standing next to me watching it
and when they this news story ended yeah the news story ended and this guy turns
to me and he says you know what that program is really about right and all I
kept thinking was a I don't know you be I thought I knew what it was about
because I watched the news story just now but I said well what what's it
supposed to be about and he says that program
is designed to deal with extraterrestrials a key absolutely
man this random guy in the Newark Airport 1983 I looked at him and I I'm
thinking you're crazy and I don't really want to talk to you that was exactly
what I was thinking I didn't say anything and he just looked at me like I
like kind of searchingly like looked at me like and then he just turned and he
he walked away and I never saw him of course so and then I promptly forgot
about that moment for the next 17 years and I remember in 2000 2001 it came back
to me in 2000 just as I was finishing the final edits of my very first book
UFOs in a national security state it came back to me and I was like my god
what was that all about who was this guy but just goes to show you you never know
stay alert young people you never know when a strange person's gonna walk up to
you and give you a premonition of your own future because that's what this guy
did to me that's really interesting crazy story huh well yeah I mean you
know we don't all talk about it these days when we're in an airport you know
when people ask us what do you do imagine back then how unusual that would
be for someone to bring up that subject yeah I think would be quite unusual and
to me he's he'll always remain this mysterious
you know person coming in from the future that's I mean obviously I don't
think that but it's it's a nice little fun fantasy I like to tell myself but I
don't know who he was and what it was or why he came up to me mm-hmm so he didn't
turn out to be a researcher that you recognize or anything like that nothing
of the sort huh so all right interesting story just put it in the gray box leave
it there I think I don't know how much more I've got for tonight what do you
think are we going through comments here we could we could take some questions
if you like maybe one maybe two let's see I fear we're gonna go too long it's
already 80 minutes I was looking into I was going to look into the Black Knight
issue a lot of people asked me about that and this was a satellite or alleged
satellite from the 1950s and 60s and you know lots of people are quick to say
they've debunked it and so forth and I don't really know what I think about the
Black Knight story I don't know what I think about the Black Knight story but I
don't know what I think about the Black Knight story but I
we still have time to think about it. I I'm going to keep it in my unknown box
right now and maybe come back to it and talk about it if if I think there's
something there that I can contribute or saying but there there we're even going
back through the 1950s there were reports of objects allegedly being
detected in Earth orbit that we're not supposed to be there and this is a
long-standing.
what the heck is this but that wasn't the first time such a thing was detected
my general feeling is that there's probably something out there that's not supposed to be
out there by our ordinary standards and i think there's probably a lot of things
that are out there that don't belong to us or to this civilization uh ivy smith asked can i expand
on why i think china and russia are part of the cover-up uh could have sworn you and other
researchers have said they have a lot more freedom in discussing ufos um there's there
have been moments in russian history where there's been a brief openness so we're talking
about dmitry medvedev for example and it's true he is i think probably still the number two man
in russia he's uh year in year out he's number two to putin he's prime minister putin's president
for a few years medvedev was president
and putin
became
president
became prime minister they reversed and and during uh i think it was either during that time
or right after he made a very famous statement at davos in 2006 where he talked about he talked
about ufos very openly to a reporter who seemed incredulous and i look at medvedev there and i
think this guy seems completely open and honest and so there are moments in uh in russian history
where
where they have been very open during the breakup of the soviet union there was a lot of openness
relatively about ufos you don't ever get that in the united states having said that it's only it
only goes up to a certain point right they still have a tremendous amount of classification about
this you can tell first of all they had kgb files on ufos back in the old days and some of those
have come out but many many more have not come out and the gru which is their successor uh you know
i i don't hear to you about any gru ufo files coming out so clearly they're they're keeping this
under wraps to some extent china same thing um china has the chinese government from what we
understand is actively monitoring all ufo groups in that country yeah so if you are a ufo researcher
in china you will have no ability to do your work without the government knowing every single thing
that you're doing
so they are on top of the whole situation it would seem there's a little more freedom in hong kong
yes yes hong kong definitely does but in terms of government openness and uh talking about this
openly i don't think there's much of a difference to be honest and russia and china are both
they're in a situation right now where they know full well they're in a basic uh kind of undeclared
geopolitical not a war but like a couple of steps below war there's definitely a major
amount of below the level strife and cyber attack on both all sides going on and all of the types
of economic warfare uh you know what americans and westerners never hear is what the united states
does to promote that agenda and i will be happy more than happy to expand on that at some point
in the future but for right now we'll just say there's
a lot of hostility going on and i think the russians and the chinese both are fundamentally
conservative governments this is what i maintain i do not i do not maintain that they are radical
looking for global revolution or anything of the sort they are status quo type countries that
simply do not want the united states to topple them right that's really their goal as i see it
so in that context i don't see a motivation
for rocking the
boat yeah don't rock the boat baby don't tip don't tip the boat over uh this is slightly
different but i remember a few years ago uh checking out one of mike barra's uh presentations
when i was traveling around to conferences by myself and he was doing comparisons of
nasa photos photos from the u.s of the moon versus uh photos from other countries of the
world he was doing comparisons of those two places where we were just in the same exact
same locations on the moon and so we were you were able to see that there was some airbrushing
going on in the u.s and the by the nasa images that's right and there wasn't in the other
countries i just thought i'd mention that because it always sort of stuck with me uh
these comparisons that he did i don't know if that's in any of his books i think i think it is
true i think nasa does have a bit of a history if it's not nasa it's just the u.s space program in general
like color correcting images and things like that yeah yeah i just thought i'd mention that i thought
that was really fascinating there's a couple of other good questions here i want to mention this
will elizondo slash or government ever release gun cam footage um with bullets and missile hits
from everything that i understand about the ttsa program and guys like louise elizondo they have
no control zero control over releasing government information uh they're not authorized to
declassify anything uh the all that they can do is try to get certain things declassified and and
if you take them at their word that's exactly what they say so their whole point is we're we are aware
of this information we have friends uh within the government who want to help us
we have enemies who don't want to help us and so that's what they're i mean this is their narrative
and what they're saying but i i don't really have any reason to
doubt that to be honest makes perfect sense to me so you've got guys who are part of ttsa
again the only one i know personally is put off and i i believe him that he wants this information
out i've known him for almost 20 years and i've talked with him quite a bit about this and
um he's been very consistent with me about this so i think if if how put off is typical of that
team and i suspect he is they probably all would like to see this information
out but they're they've only got so much pull they're not you know they're a couple of
uh a small group of retired people with some connections to the intelligence field but it
doesn't mean that they can just declassify willy-nilly so i don't know that's up to the
pentagon up to the cia it's up to whomever has control over these uh videos and whether and
when and how they will be released is a great question i don't know the answer any others
um let's see interested to hear richard's view of the nimitz reports of objects descending
from space to 28 000 feet then sea level ours or theirs oh yeah well my goodness that's very
important stuff and we've known about this now for over a year the objects that are descending from
upper upper atmosphere down to 28 000 feet down to sea level i do personally do not believe that
they are ours
believe that they are from anything having to do with the black budget of
the United States or any other country and I suppose you could say that there
is a rogue human breakaway civilization that has no part of any government
that's doing this I mean my goodness I hypothesize the existence of such a
thing many years ago but that it's different to hypothesize it than to say
that this object is definitely from that my feeling is that this is not our
technology and it's beyond human I believe it's extraterrestrial so Brian
white have you talked with Elizondo I know we would like to yeah I've never
I've not ever spoken with Louise Elizondo we have a couple of mutual
friends a couple of mutual contacts and that's it but I've never had a
conversation with him I've never sought him out I mean it's possible he
be willing to talk with me or it's possible he wouldn't the that whole crew
the whole ttsa crowd it's very obvious they're not interested in the UFO people
anymore and i think you know from their point of view and this is how they're
going to see it they roll out some information they totally stumbled right
at the starting line fell on their face with some really bad mistake so they
didn't help themselves obviously but they
out they provided information and from their perspective found themselves being
attacked by practically every UFO researcher out there they're thinking
hey wait a minute we're just trying to help the cause here maybe make a little
money on the side undoubtedly but what's the big deal is their attitude and so I
think that they were the impression that I get is that they were kind of taken
aback by the very very strong attacks that were levied against them by so many
people and I I had a lot of suspicions about them I still do and I I'm voicing
them now I think that I think that what they're doing is as I've said part of a
controlled disclosure that is not entirely honest but that's different
from seeing them out as the bad guys and the black hats like they're they're
playing a part
Right
and so we have to play a part as well and our part is to we've got to push we
have to push them and we have to push not just them but the government
agencies because they're not the same as the government mm-hmm you know they're
they are they have connections with that mm-hmm government but government's big
it's got a lot of actors involved there a lot of different moving parts I think
we should push in a way that they can talk you know knowing that they're all
bound by something if we can push in areas that we know they can talk in well
for example I've had almost 20 years of attempts of speaking with Hal Puthoff and
I can tell you right now he'll he'll tell me what he wants to tell me and he
won't tell me what he doesn't want to tell me and it's that simple right so I
I've been I've tried every approach I've been sweet and coy and batted my eyes
many times and I've been direct and blunt
like a sledgehammer and there's no difference like it doesn't really make a
difference like I will ask questions I get some information and then I don't
get what is what he doesn't sure how's bound by things but he's also kind of a
low-profile kind of guy he's always like that right very much so very much so
it's not like him to just sort of come out and you know no and he knows I
respect him and where he's coming from and when he can't tell me something he
can't tell me I mean right as much as that's what it is but
and he's not the only person I've chatted with from his circle but
they're all that way they all they all have lived in that world and Elizondo is
no different he's a career intelligence officer so they know full well what they
are able to discuss and what they are absolutely not able to discuss and they
have to negotiate a very careful discourse within what is allowed and I'm sure that's the way it is.
They want to maintain a certain high level of integrity and credibility on
many sides sort of you know what I mean? Yeah yeah they do and you know integrity
is a tough one to define because for them defending their interest you know
that that might mean having to be deceptive for the public and but to
defend certain larger interests as they see it and. Right.
So there's I guess what I would just say is it's complicated. I think we make a big
mistake when we divide people into white hats and black hats. Yeah. You see this
all the time in this field and I I'm not a fan of it I think it it causes us to
take sides and therefore to be oppositional to people where sometimes
you need to work with people that aren't your best friend. Right. Like you've got
to work with them and you've got to be able to learn
from them. Yeah.
Someone asked Richard Doty and put off. Yeah I wanted to show you that.
I've said this. Did I hear Richard Doty recently said he worked for how put off
for 11 years? I'd like to know under what exact conditions that took place because
I that's news to me. I would not have thought that at all. Okay. I'm gonna have
to send an email out now. Did Doty work for you? Yeah right. All right another one
here. What does Richard think about NMSA?
Am I supposed to know and NYMSA? I didn't know the acronym. So I'm out of I'm out of the loop. So anything else? Have I covered the 1941
Cape Girardeau? We've talked about it and someone's asking you to talk about
Dyatlov Pass. Oh Dyatlov Pass. And then then we'll do this. I'm gonna do this.
See? He knows. I'll get too excited and so yes just as a follow-up to last week
I was saying we were I was looking into Dyatlov Pass and I got an email that said this is related to the
and I am so deep into that right now I've got two books going on and I'm deep
into a website that some of you might know I think it's D out love org I've
had it open for so long I can't remember exactly what it is but this woman who is
Russian translated every single document so I'm looking into that if you don't
know we talked about this last week 1959 incredible crazy disappearance not
disappearance but death of nine hikers hikers hikers years so mysterious
everything that happens so I'm slowly going through the it's not even like a
UFO thing no this is beyond anything like that it's like nothing makes sense
yes that's the case that you know if you really want to get into it you can watch
some YouTube videos but even the best one I found out there now that I am
reading the direct
accounts because there were journals recovered there were pictures from their
cameras and there's a whole bunch of evidence once you go through the very
best one that was on YouTube immediately has to be cast out as a theory of what
happened right none of them none of them are good there are over accurate seventy
five different theories what happened this went through a criminal
investigation of forensic investigation and no one has ever been able excuse me
to determine what happened this went through a criminal investigation of a forensic investigation and no one has ever been able excuse me to determine
what happened to these nine hikers uh it is a fascinating story with fascinating components it's
i mean it's horrible it's a lot of people are mentioning the missing tongue there was one
missing tongue there was yeah there was one but you know what that i know i mentioned a few things
last week that was barely scratching the surface there are so many fascinating things about this
case and um we are going to do it i just i want to make sure we go through absolutely everything
that we can and uh so that we can present everything to you yeah one thing we don't i
don't want to do we don't want to do is like a totally half-assed job of presenting it and saying
oh well we have a couple of ideas here so but tracy has been throwing herself into it like this
is great for me because i'm not doing any of the research i tell them about it every night yeah so
that's good this theory can't be because this happened and this happened i mean you go through
every phase of this and it is amazing what the
these nine people went through i mean nothing makes sense so you're right it's ufos were uh one
of the theories because there were some sightings in the area however that's not the most interesting
theory no so it has a it has a 411 david polities kind of thing kind of a feel to it yeah it really
does but uh very bizarre excuse me now that i'm into it this is such uh an incredible mysterious
um horrifying in many ways case but we will do this it is fascinating you're watching people yeah
a lot of everyone's asking about david adair maybe we'll come back to it we'll come back to
david adair i'm not an expert i'm familiar with him we'll get into david adair maybe one day it's
a few other things am i going to do a missing 411 we've been trying for a long time how about this
either an interview or an overview if it's an overview i'll get to piss off polities himself
because like we'll do it and then maybe we'll do it and then we'll do it and then we'll do it and
we'll we'll get him back i want to interview him i've been trying to get david he agreed originally
but you know he's just he's busy so i'm a big fan of david pilates work big fan i've read four or
five of his books now and uh you want some creepy nighttime reading go start with those freaked me
out but now that i i am into diatlov pass that that it that takes the cake for me and someone
mentioned martin stubbs i'll look for him too i'm a i'm very interested in his work okay and walter
bosley okay we'll look for walter bosley i think we got to wrap this up it is now time we do okay
anything else we want to tell people nah obviously i still have a cough your cough is still it's
getting better it's still here all night i was trying because in the very beginning i was i
didn't say a word because i didn't want to breathe in because i could feel it i was such a hard ass
before we started like i heard tracy cough five minutes before and i was like did you take your
what is that mucinex i don't know what it's whatever i call it i don't like taking your cough
i don't like taking stuff like that but just for this i said you have to i took a half you did a
pretty good job it was you did a pretty good job you're good but um look as far as as far as the uh
the space base uh material look there's so much more and it's always a frustrating endeavor to
talk about this a because it gets contentious everyone's got these strong opinions and and it's
totally possible that one or two of the cases we mentioned may not be that anomalous it's
going to be that we'll grant that but i think that there are there's a strong foundation for
space-based anomalies and i think we need to be looking at that and we should be coming back to
more of these in the future i agree i agree yeah check out the intelligent disclosure t-shirt
i'm not always a t-shirt guy but uh i like this one yeah we sell them we had to order one of our
own because the way this works we we don't have we don't have the stock of them so we ordered them to
make sure we like them and richard loves this i do i like it a lot i mean it's not even what it is
he loves the actual feel of the t-shirt it feels so good against my skin god i'm getting him started
okay sorry uh excuse me anyhow um i think we should wrap this up let's wrap it up before
i say something else to get myself in trouble excuse me youtube's looking for an excuse we
know this i know i have to be careful about the language but i think we're safe we chose something
safe are you talking about this it's word art in here just for fun we want to do something uh
yeah different and we did it because we really love this show and you know some people had asked
for it and so we were inspired by you guys and um this is what we created so yeah i think we like it
my mom thinks it's cool um so want to thank everyone for being here i'm sorry we we aren't
able to be in the chat when we do this but
uh we can see you we know you're all there and uh we we're so grateful for all of you we're so
grateful for everyone who doesn't get to watch it live uh who watches this later um just being here
um lets us know that you support the show absolutely thank you for that and you support
richard's research thank you which we really appreciate i'm coming back on saturday and
i'm just getting in the mood for some craziness i have a feeling i'm going to be
he's got some things building i will tell you the old richard dolan show style
that's i think that's coming back yeah yeah yeah but um thanks again to everyone thank you
to pursuing x uh as always for helping us with the questions those would be moderating us i'm
sorry i cut you no that's it support us support our work what we do we're very grateful for that
and if you like what you see here subscribe to the channel we just hit 60 000 subscribers
finally and it seemed like it took forever those last few days tell them why it's
important for us well it's important i mean not just for personal ego you're talking about for
actual professional things professional things seriously this is a serious subject it requires
serious attention and we're not going to get serious attention if we don't have enough
followers that's just the way it is social media is like that's the currency i know it's not crazy
that is the new currency but it's all about the way it is yeah honestly on a personal level i
could care less how many subscribers i have but that's the way it is yeah that's the way it is
i have that's the truth right my mother thinks it's awesome my mother's like she doesn't care
about the ufo stuff she's just like you have lots of fans out there i'm like uh doing okay mom
but what i care about what i only care about is getting this word out to as many people as
possible and the way to do that is subscribers and likes like if you like what you see here
then hit the like button and subscribe for notifications we just want to thank everybody who
already has because we're going to have a lot of people that are going to be watching this and we're
going to have a lot of people that are going to be watching this and we're going to have a lot of people
we know a lot of you already have and uh we do we thank you for that we thank you for your support
and one of these days i'm going to give a little talk about my mother oh he did that on the cruise
anybody who was on the cruise with us got full mother stories now look here's the thing everyone's
got a mom that's a little crazy let's face it that's what mothers are but mine you don't know
until you see my mom i love my mother she's the best but uh we both have great mom here's the
thing you could drop her in the comments below and i would love to hear what you think about it
you could drop her in the comments below and i would love to hear what you think about it
into any sitcom and she would be the funniest character in the show dominate she would
dominate she would dominate wouldn't even try she wouldn't even have to break a sweat
dominate wouldn't even try she wouldn't even have to break a sweat
dominate wouldn't even try she wouldn't even have to break a sweat that's my mother so i should come
that's my mother so i should come
that's my mother so i should come back and tell some some mom stories every
back and tell some some mom stories every
back and tell some some mom stories every now and then we'll leave that to you
now and then we'll leave that to you
now and then we'll leave that to you yeah i don't know if your mom would like
yeah i don't know if your mom would like
that i don't know we'll have to find out but that'll be i talked to her just the other day and
she is that she does not slow down that's the thing she just keeps going she's almost 80 and
you wouldn't know she just is constantly in motion she walks with a forward tilt like this like
groucho mark just moving forward with all of her opposable fingers and thumbs like ready to grab
things and do things and she does she walks super super fast she is kind of in this forward
it's true tracy wonders where i get my energy from well i don't anymore
if it's from my mother yeah i always thought he was an energizer bunny until i met
energizer mummy she's out of control not really so okay we should wrap this up all right we should
uh thank you everyone for coming out and we'll catch you next time until then stay sane stay brave
and
don't let the grind you down it's great spending the evening with all of you take care